<Module name="sketch">
<Class name="Sketch" super="wigs.papplet.PApplet">Represents an interactive, animation that runs in the Pygame window.
	<PropR name=""></PropR>
	<PropA name=""></PropA>
	<Method name="" inherit="papplet.PApplet"/>
	<Method name="" return="">
		<Arg name=""></Arg>
	</Method>
</Class>
<Class name="Sprite">Represents a graphical object or character capable of interaction.
	<PropR name="a">a</PropR>
	<PropA name="b">b</PropA>
	<Method name="c">c
		<Arg name="d">d</Arg>
	</Method>
</Class>

<Function name="flipAll(imgs, xflip, yflip) → list"><span>Performs a horizontal and/or vertical flip on a sequence of <code>Image</code> instances. Returns a new <code>list</code> of images.</span>
	<Arg name="imgs">A sequence of images.</Arg>
	<Arg name="xflip" default="False">Indicates whether to flip the images horizontally.</Arg>
	<Arg name="yflip" default="False">Indicates whether to flip the images vertically.</Arg>
</Function>

<Function name="onResize(sk, ev) → float">This is the default event handler function for VIDEORESIZE events. The function scales all sprite properties to the resized sketch size and returns the scale factor.
	<Arg name="sk">A reference to the <code>Sketch</code> instance.</Arg>
	<Arg name="ev">A reference to the <code>pygame.event.EventType</code> object.</Arg>
</Function>

<Function name="" return="">
	<Arg name="" default=""></Arg>
</Function>

<Function name="" return="">
	<Arg name="" default=""></Arg>
</Function>

<Constant name="VISIBLE"><span>Used as a <code>Sprite</code> instance’s <code>status</code> property to indicate that the sprite is to be drawn and updated.</span></Constant>
<Constant name="HIDDEN"><span>Used as a <code>Sprite</code> instance’s <code>status</code> property to indicate that the sprite is to be updated but not drawn.</span></Constant>
<Constant name="DISABLED"><span>Used as a <code>Sprite</code> instance’s <code>status</code> property to indicate that the sprite is not to be drawn or updated.</span></Constant>
<Constant name="ENABLED">Indicates that a sprite is not disabled.</Constant>
<Constant name="NO_EDGE">Indicates no action to be taken when the sprite reaches the edge of the sketch.</Constant>
<Constant name="BOUNCE">Indicates that the sprite bounces from the edge of the sketch.</Constant>
<Constant name="WRAP">Indicates that the sprite wraps to the far edge when crossing an edge of the sketch.</Constant>
<Constant name="REMOVE">Indicates that the sprite is to be removed when it leaves the sketch area.</Constant>

</Module>
