<Module name="papplet">
<Class name="PApplet"><span>Represents an interactive animation that runs in the Pygame window and is modelled on <span class="Link" onclick="window.open('http://www.processing.org')">Processing’s</span> <code>PApplet</code> class. <code class="Link" onclick="goRef('sketch','Sketch')">Sketch</code> and <code class="Link" onclick="goRef('physics','Environment')">Environment</code> are subclasses which extend <code>PApplet</code>.</span>
	<Method name="PApplet(setup, draw, eventMap)"><span>The constructor creates a <code>PApplet</code> instance. Use the <code>run</code> method to run the sketch.</span>
		<Arg name="setup(sk)" default="None">An unbound function that initializes the sketch.
			<Arg name="sk">A reference to the sketch.</Arg>
		</Arg>
		<Arg name="draw(sk)" default="None">An unbound function that draws one frame of the animation.
			<Arg name="sk">A reference to the sketch.</Arg>
		</Arg>
		<Arg name="eventMap" default="None"><span>A dictionary that maps event types or classes (keys) to handler functions (values). You can use <code>None</code> as a key to specify a handler for events that do not have a custom handler.</span></Arg>
	</Method>
	<Method name="setBackground(bgImage, bgColor)">Set the sketch background.
		<Arg name="bgImage" default="None">An image to be used for the sketch background. The sketch aspect ratio will be locked (except when maximized) to match the background image.</Arg>
		<Arg name="bgColor" default="None">A color to be drawn as the background. If both arguments are given, the image will be blitted onto a background of the specified color.</Arg>
	</Method>
	<Method name="run(size, caption, icon, mode)">Run the sketch.
		<Arg name="size" default="(512,288)">The initial size of the sketch in pixels.</Arg>
		<Arg name="caption" default="&quot;Sketch&quot;">A string specifying the caption for the sketch window.</Arg>
		<Arg name="icon" default="None">The path to an image to be used as the window icon.</Arg>
		<Arg name="mode" default="pygame.RESIZABLE"><span>Change to <code>0</code> to make the sketch non-resizable.</span></Arg>
	</Method>
	<PropR name="frameCount"><span>The total number of frames that have been drawn (including the current frame).</span></PropR>
	<PropR name="draw" default="drawBackground"><span>A reference to the current drawing function; set by the constructor to the function passed as the <code>draw</code> argument.</span></PropR>
	<PropR name="eventMap" default="{}"><span>A dictionary that maps event types (keys) to handler functions (values); set by the constructor to the dictionary passed as the <code>eventMap</code> argument.</span></PropR>
</Class>

</Module>
